Indiana University President Emeritus John W. Ryan papers, 1944-2011 C456
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University President Emeritus John W. Ryan papers
1944-2011
1988-2007
Indiana University Archives
Ryan, John W. (John William), 1929-2011
C456
22.2 cubic feet 23 boxes
John Ryan was Indiana University's 14th president and served the institution for 30 years. Ryan was instrumental in the creation and inaugurals of eight I.U. charter campuses. This collection consists of Dr. Ryan's president emeritus records, including documents concerning his activities in international affairs and speeches he gave between 1987-2011.
Access Restrictions
Select files closed to researchers.
Advance notice required for access to collection.
Biographical Note
John William Ryan was born on August 12, 1929, in Chicago, Illinois. He received a bachelor's degree from the University of Utah in 1951. Ryan came to Indiana University as a graduate student in 1951. He received a master's degree in 1958 and a Ph.D. in 1959, both in political science, at IU. He was a research analyst in the Department of Revenue for the Commonwealth of Kentucky, 1953- 55; research associate in the I.U. Program in Public Administration in Thailand, 1955-57; Assistant Director of the Institute of Training for Public Service on the Bloomington Campus, 1957-58; Associate Director, Bureau of Government, University of Wisconsin, 1958-62; Executive Assistant to the President and University Secretary, University of Massachusetts, Amherst, 1962-63; Vice- President for Academic Affairs, Arizona State University, 1963-65; and Chancellor, University of Massachusetts, Boston, 1965-68. In July, 1968 Ryan become Vice- President and Chancellor for Regional Campuses. Dr. John W. Ryan was elected fourteenth president of Indiana University on January 26, 1971. One of the hallmarks of Ryan's administration was the development of the campuses at Fort Wayne, South Bend, Gary (Northwest), Kokomo, and Jeffersonville (Southeast) from extension centers to degree-granting divisions. During his tenure, a cooperative program of long standing in Richmond was launched as the University's sixth regional campus.
After announcing his retirement as President in 1986, Ryan continued an active public role as a liaison, public speaker, and representative for IU. Dr. John Ryan passed away on Saturday morning, August 6, 2011 at IU Health Bloomington Hospital. He was married to his wife Patricia for 62 years, and the couple had three children: Kathleen, Kevin, and Kerrick.
Portions of this Biography taken from "The Investiture of John W. Ryan as Fourteenth President of Indiana University" Program.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series: Office files, Speeches, Correspondence, and Travel files.
Scope and Content Note
John Ryan's Indiana University President Emeritus papers span the period from 1984 through 2011 and are organized into four series: Office files, Speeches, Correspondence, and Travel files.
The first series, Office files, span the period from 1944-2011 with the bulk of files created within the years 1988-2000. Substantial files pertain to NCAA activities and to Ryan's "Presidential Commission" duties. Other notable files include those on the International Council, Indiana University Foundation (IUF), his affiliation with the Alumni Association, the National Advisory Board on International Education Programs, and The Rement Trust.
The second series is made up of the speeches given by Dr. Ryan from 1984-2010. Included are his keynote address at the first annual meeting of Indiana Sister Cities, his speech for the International Association of Universities at the University of Combra (Portugal) and the University of Salamaca (Spain) in April of 1993, and his speech at a colloquium on the "Globalization of Higher Edcuation," in Istanbul, Turkey. Not all of the speeches in this series are directly related to University life or Indiana, Ryan also spoke at retirement dinners and memorial gatherings for friends and colleagues. The series also contains the speeches he made as Chancellor of the State University of New York, a position he held from 1996-1999.
The third series is Ryan's correspondence files written by John Ryan from 1988-2011. This series is organized in two sub-series: Chronological copies and Alpha copies. Chronological copies are those letters filed by date written, while Alpha files are copies of letters filed by the recipient's last name. Many of the letter consists of expression of thanks and gratitude to an individual who participated in a Ryan sponsored event. Some are congratulatory messages from Ryan to individuals who recently received some form of professional recognition. Other topics include Indiana football, international trips, and involvement in organizations such as the International Association of Universities.
Known as a president very much involved in IU system expansion, Ryan did a lot of work overseas to develop an international identity for the university. Series four contains files related to Dr. Ryan's travels to conferences and board meetings outside the United States, and spans the period from 1988-2006. Files within this series include those pertaining to the Hungarian accreditation committee advisory board, United Arab Emirates University, and the International Council within the Indiana University Foundation.
Separated Material
The "Oral History" series, which consisted of duplicates of transcribed interviews and video-recordings of emeriti faculty from Indiana University 1991-1997, was permanently removed from this collection in January 2019. The original oral histories can be found in the Indiana University Oral History Collection at the IU Center for Documentary Research and Practice at the IU Media School.
Related Material
Additional records such as newsletters, annual reports, bulletins, and publications may be accessed in the Archives of Institutional Memory
Related photographs may be available in the University Archives Photographs Database
Acquisition Information
Accession numbers: 2011/132
Provenance
Records were transferred to the IU Archives in October 2011.
College presidents --Indiana --History --Sources.; Indiana University. Office of the President Emeritus; Ryan, John W. (John William), 1929-2011 -- Archives; Ryan, John W. (John William), 1929-2011 -- Correspondence; Indiana University -- Presidents -- History -- Sources
- Office files, 1944-2011 (Box 1)
  - A, 1988-2007 (Box 1)
  - Academy for Educational Development (AED) Panama, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Admissions-Policy & Recruiting, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - The Adventure Center at Belmont - Fritz Harbridge, August 29. 2006 (Box 1)
  - Alabama Power Company, Industrial Interchange Executive Conf. "Discovering A New World", September. 18-20, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Alliance of Distinguished Rank Professors, 1978-2011 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association, Indiana University (Box 1)
    - General, 1989-2007 (Box 1)
    - Cream and Crimson Alumni Weekend (John W. Ryan hosts Sen. Birch Bayh) (Box 1)
    - Cream and Crimson Alumni Weekend/ DASA, June 16-18, 2006 (Box 1)
    - Distinguished Alumni Service Award, June 19-21, 2009 (Box 1)
    - Distinguished Alumni Service Award (DASA) (Box 1)
      - 2005-2010 (Box 1)
      - 2002-2004 (Box 1)
    - Distinguished Alumni Service Award Club (DASA) (Box 1)
      - 1997-2001 (Box 1)
      - 1988-1996 (Box 1)
  - AMARA Raksasataya National Institute of Development Admin Bangkok, Thailand (see also NIDA), 1988-1991 (Box 1)
  - American Cancer Society University Leadership Development Conference, at Brown County State Park, June 3, 1992 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education, 1995 (Box 1)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) (Box 1)
    - General File, 2011 (Box 1)
    - Hubert H. Humphrey Award, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - American Society for Public Administration (ASPA), 1990 (Box 1)
  - Associates in Rural Development, Inc., 1995-1998 (Box 1)
  - The American University of the Jordan (AUJ) The American University of Palestine, 1996-2005 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Hans, 1995-2007 (Box 1)
  - Angola High School Annual Academic Awards Banquet (John W. Ryan speaker), May 22, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Arizona State University (Box 1)
    - Intercollegiate Athletics Report to the President Dallas, TX, August 11, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Review of ASU Intercollegiate Athletics Department (John W. Ryan Special Advisor to President Lattie Coor), 1993 (Box 1)
  - Art Museum (IU) National Advisory Board, 2006-2011 (Box 1)
  - Asian Student Group, Council of Faculty Advisors, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Aspire International Advisory Board (NAFSA Association of International Educators), 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Association for Asian Studies, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Association for Fraternity Advisors, Robert H. Shaffer Award, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Association of American Universities, 1995-2000 (Box 1)
  - Association Liaison Office, Campus Advisory Group (Box 1)
    - To A.I.D. Center F04 University Cooperation in Development, 1992 (Box 1)
    - John Ryan Chair 9-4, January 6, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Arts and Sciences, College of, 2001-2010 (Box 1)
  - Athletics (Box 2)
    - General, 2004-2011 (Box 2)
    - Basketball, 1993-2003 (Box 2)
    - Football (Box 2)
      - General, 1992-2010 (Box 2)
      - Peach Bowl 1990 Atlanta, GA December 27-30 (Box 2)
      - Liberty Bowl in Memphis, December 28, 1988 (Box 2)
      - Peach Bowl, December 31, 1987-January 2, 1988 (Box 2)
  - B, 1995-2006 (Box 2)
  - Ball State, Beneficience Celebration, Rededication Muncie, IN. (John W. Ryan speaker), September 26, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Banet, Father Charles (Celebration Honoring), June 27, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Bareikis, Robert P., 1989-1992 (Box 2)
  - Barker, Sarah Evans, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Batman Scholarship (Howard T. Batman), 1992-2010 (Box 2)
  - Big Ten Gathering: Focusing Our Future, John W. Ryan speaker), February 26-28, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Bill, Daniel J. "Dan", 1984 (Box 2)
  - Bloomington, Mayor of the City of, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Bonser, Charles, 1988-2005 (Box 2)
  - Boy Scouts of America, 1988-1999 (Box 2)
  - Bradford Woods (Box 2)
    - General, 2007-2010 (Box 2)
    - Friends of, 2009- (Box 2)
  - Business, School of (Box 2)
    - General File, 1997-2011 (Box 2)
    - The W. George Pinnel Professorship, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Canterbury School Commencement, Fort Wayne, Indiana, June 10, 1988 (Box 2)
  - C, 1993-2003 (Box 2)
  - Carmichael, Hoagy (Box 2)
    - Sculpture Project, 2004-2008 (Box 2)
    - Title: The Stardust Road Project Director: Patricia C. Kellar, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Center for University Studies, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Chemistry, Department of, 1988-1993 (Box 2)
  - China - Delegation of Education Officials from Zhejiang Province, PRC to the State of Indiana, May 1988 (Box 2)
  - China Correspondence, 1997-2007 (Box 2)
  - Christmas Gift-Thank You's, 1987-2009 (Box 2)
  - Circle for Excellence, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Commencement (Box 2)
    - IUPUI - John W. Ryan to escort Dr. P Fisher-Appelt, May 10, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Bloomington (John W. Ryan Receives Honorary Degree), May 6-7, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Committee: All University Committee on Names, 1997-2010 (Box 2)
  - Communication and Marketing, Office of, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Congratulations (Box 2)
    - 2000-2009 (Box 2)
    - 1988-1997 (Box 2)
  - Corporation for Indiana's International Future, Inc., 1988 (Box 2)
  - Corporation for Indiana's International Future--Monday Governor's Office, February 15, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Corrigan, Robert A., President San Francisco State University, 1989-1994 (Box 3)
  - Council of Ten, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, Inc. (CFR) (John W. Ryan Nominated for membership by Herman B Wells,), 1993 (Box 3)
  - D, 1987-2010 (Box 3)
  - Daly, Walter, Retirement of Walter Daly, October 31, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Danielson, Donald C. (Danny), 1990-2010 (Box 3)
  - Day planner, 1988-2009; (12 folders) (Box 3)
  - Day planner, 2010 (Box 3a)
  - Drake University (Commission on the Future of), 1987-1988 (Box 3a)
  - Durham Lecture Brigham Young University, February 21, 1990 (Box 3a)
  - Dye, James W., 1993-2003 (Box 3a)
  - E, 1991-1993 (Box 3a)
  - IDP Education Australia (Papua New Guinea Assignment) & EDC, 1996-1997 (Box 3a)
  - Education Development Center, Inc. (EDC) (Papua New Guinea High Education Project) (Box 3a)
    - General, 1993-1996 (Box 3a)
    - Papua New Guinea, reports, 1994 (Box 3a)
    - Documents, 1994 (Box 3a)
    - PNG Higher Education Project (Personal Letters), 1994 (Box 3a)
  - Education, School of (Box 3a)
    - (Indiana Education Policy Center), 1989-2011 (Box 3a)
    - The Center for Research & p-16 Collaboration, 2007-2009 (Box 3a)
  - Egan, John B. (& Anne Marie), 1996-2010 (Box 3a)
  - Employment (Interest in John W. Ryan), 1987-1994 (Box 3a)
  - Emeriti House (Box 3a)
    - (IUB, 1015 E. Atwater) Governance Committee, 2004-2007 (Box 3a)
    - Oral History Project, 1996-2007 (Box 3a)
    - Question Guideline: Emeriti Faculty Interviews, 2004 (Box 3a)
    - Emeriti Faculty Interviews, 2005-2006 (Box 3a)
    - Emeriti Oral History Group Meeting, September 2, 2005 (Box 3a)
    - Emeriti Interview Meeting and Lunch, October 24, 2004 (Box 3a)
  - Executive Sports-Lori A. McQueen, 1997 (Box 3a)
  - F, 1988-2002 (Box 3a)
  - Fourth Annual Henry Ferrettie Memorial, Inc. Dinner & Award Ceremony, South Bend, IN (John W. Ryan Speaker), October 5, 1989 (Box 3a)
  - Fisher-Appelt, Peter, 1990-2010 (Box 3a)
  - Foundation for the International Exchange of Scientific & Cultural Information by Telecommunications, 1987 (Box 3a)
  - Florida Atlantic University- General, 1989-1991 (Box 3a)
  - Florida International University, 2004-2008 (Box 3a)
  - Founders Day, 1994-2004 (Box 3a)
  - G, 1988-1994 (Box 3a)
  - Global Market Opportunities Conference Blacksburg, VA Monday, May 4, 1992 (Box 3a)
  - Globalization Materials & Info gathered, August, 2008 (Box 3a)
  - Governmental Relations, 1988 (Box 3a)
  - Greek Walk Dedication, October 7, 1995 (Box 3a)
  - Guruz, Kemal MS, 2006-2011 (Box 3a)
  - Gutman's 50th Wedding Anniversary Celebration- Fort Wayne Country Club, Sat. 6:00pm, Sept. 3, 2005 (Box 3a)
  - H, 1988-1995 (Box 3a)
  - Haeberle, William National Entrepreneurship Foundation, 2007 (Box 3a)
  - Harmony School, 2003-2009 (Box 3a)
  - Hatch, Garn, 1987-1989 (Box 3a)
  - Health Research and Service Institute at Fort Wayne (Bod Hutner & Dan Bill), 1992-1996 (Box 3a)
  - Hetherington, Peter, 1995-2005 (Box 4)
  - Hoosiers for Higher Education (IN State Fair), 2007 (Box 4)
  - Honorary Degree (Recommendations, Misc.), 1994-2010 (Box 4)
  - Housing Task Force (Housing for Students at IU Regional Campuses), 1989-1990 (Box 4)
  - Huber, Doug, 1980-2001 (Box 4)
  - Hungarian Accreditation Committee Meeting (Box 4)
    - Budapest, Hungary, 1994 (Box 4)
    - General, May 6-7, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Hungarian Studies Institute, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Huntington College Foundation Banquet Thursday, September 8, 1988 (Box 4)
  - I, 1992-1995 (Box 4)
  - Inkenberry, Stanley, 1987-1996 (Box 4)
  - IMHE Conference, Washington, D.C., Organization for Economic Co-operation & Development, October, 1994 (Box 4)
  - The Indiana Academy (Box 4)
    - 2000-2007 (Box 4)
    - 1987-1999 (Box 4)
  - Indiana Lectures, 1999 (Box 4)
  - IU Foundation (Box 4)
    - General File, 1988-2011 (Box 4)
    - 1820 Society, 2007 (Box 4)
    - The Campaign for Indiana, 1987-1989 (Box 4)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on an International Council General File, 1991-1994 (Box 4)
    - Indiana University Foundation Presidential Search, 1991 (Box 4)
    - IUF: Recreational Sports Facility (& Aquatic), 1989 (Box 4)
  - International Council (Box 4)
    - Meeting, May 18-19, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Founding Meeting, February 13-15, 1992 (Box 4)
    - Bloomington 8:30-11:30 A.M.- Sat., Oct. 27, 1990 (Box 4)
    - IUF: International Council Meeting Thursday, 1:30 p.m. International Council Task Force, June 13, 1991; Sept/Oct 1991 (Box 4)
    - Committee on and International Council, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on an International council- AT&T Building, New York Thursday, May 24, 1990 (Box 4)
    - IUF: International Council Preliminary Meeting 3:00pm Thursday, August 9, 1990 (Box 4)
  - International Association of Universities (IAU) (Box 4)
    - General, 1989 (Box 4)
    - Coimbra/Salamanca Seminar (Portugal & Spain) (see foreign travel files), April 18-24, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Helsinki, Finland, August 5-11, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Indiana University's International Forum: Washington, D.C., October 18, 1995 (Box 4)
  - International Programs (Box 4)
    - La Caixa, 1986-1995 (Box 4)
    - General, 1987-2004 (Box 4)
    - AID "Atlas" Proposal (African Training for Leadership and Advanced Skills), 1990 (Box 4)
    - International Programs at Indiana: Serving State Needs Through Academic Excellence, 1990-1992 (Box 4)
  - Initiative for Global Development, 2005-2008 (Box 4)
  - Ivy Tech State College, 2001-2011 (Box 4)
  - J, 1989-1997 (Box 4)
  - Visit of the Ambassador of Japan-His Excellency Takakazu Kuriyama-Opening of Japan/US 2nd Annual Business Camp, July 14, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Jones, Frank (Friends of Franklin), 1988-2004 (Box 5)
  - Jordan, Bryce - President Emeritus Pennsylvania State University., 1995 (Box 5)
  - K, 1988-1991 (Box 5)
  - Kampen, Emerson (and members of the Kampen family), 1988-1996 (Box 5)
  - Kessler, Sherm, 1994-2007 (Box 5)
  - Kinsey Institute for Research in Sex, Gender, & Reproduction General, 1996-2006 (Box 5)
    - By-Laws, 1994-1996 (Box 5)
    - Reinisch, June M., 1991-1995 (Box 5)
  - Knight, Robert M., 2000-2011 (Box 5)
  - Korn/Ferry International, 1988-1999 (Box 5)
  - L, 1989-2002 (Box 5)
  - Lions Club Speech at Carol Stream IL, Thursday, December 3, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Liu, John S. K. (potential interest in IU China Studies Center Relationship between National Defense University, Beijing, China and Indiana University, 1988-1990 (Box 5)
  - Langevin, Thomas H. Langevin & Associates, Inc. (registry for interim college & university Presidents), 1992-2010 (Box 5)
  - Leadership- Orientation, October 7, 2004 (Box 5)
  - Liaison Committee of Medical Education (LCME), 1989-2000 (Box 5)
  - Libraries, Indiana University, 2001-2010 (Box 5)
  - Lilly Endowment, 1989-1993 (Box 5)
  - Lombardi, John V., 1989-2005 (Box 5)
  - Inauguration of John P. Lombardi, Feb 6 & 7, 2003 (Box 5)
  - Lucas, Robert A "Bob", 1988-1995 (Box 5)
  - M, 1996-2005 (Box 5)
  - Mckinstry, William J., 1988 (Box 5)
  - Metropolitan Universities, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Midwestern Universities Alliance (Newton O. Catteli), 1989-1994 (Box 5)
  - Inaugural Celebration for Dr. Peggy Gordon Elliott University of Akron Friday, May 7, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
  - Mitchell, Hall, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Montgomery, John D. (also See: Soka University), 1995-2002 (Box 5)
  - Morris, James T., 1996-2000 (Box 5)
  - Midwest Universities Consortium for International Activities, Inc. (MUCIA), 1994-1996 (Box 5)
  - Muhler, Joseph C., 1989-1990 (Box 5)
  - Murphy, MSGR. Terrence J. A Catholic University: Vision and Opportunities University of St.Thomas, 2001 (Box 5)
  - Music, School of, 1992-2010 (Box 5)
  - Mutz, Thomas R. and Joyce, 1993 (Box 5)
  - N, 1998-2007 (Box 5)
  - National Academy of Public Administration (Box 5)
    - General File, 2004-2008 (Box 5)
    - Spring Meeting, Indianapolis, June 4-5, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Fall Meeting, Washington, D.C., November 9-10, 1990 (Box 5)
  - National Advisory Board on International Education Programs (Box 6)
    - General, 1987 (Box 6)
    - Meeting Washington, D.C., October 18, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Board Meeting, April 29, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Board Meeting, November 6, 1987 (Box 6)
    - General, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
    - Meeting, April 6-7, 1989 (Box 6)
  - National Advisory Council for the National Foreign Language Center (Box 6)
    - 1987-1993 (Box 6)
    - October 21, 1988 (Box 6)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (Box 6)
    - General File, 1993-1999 (Box 6)
    - Guild of former presidents (Counselors on Univ. Gov.), 1989-1993 (Box 6)
    - Commission on International Affairs Meeting, Washington, D.C. (John W. Ryan Speaker), July 12-14, 1992 (Box 6)
    - Annual Meeting, New Orleans, LA, November 8-10, 1992 (Box 6)
    - Annual Meeting & Dinner & Mtg. of the Board of Directors of Emeritus Service Project, November 19-21, 1989 (Box 6)
    - Annual Meeting Tuesday, November 10, 1987 (Box 6)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association (Box 6)
    - General File, 1987-1993 (Box 6)
    - Study on Intercollegiate Athletics September, 1987 (Box 6)
    - Study on Intercollegiate Athletics March, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Presidents Commission, Atlanta, GA, April 6-7, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Forum, Orlando, FL, June 20-21, 1988 (Box 6)
    - President Commission legislative Subcommittee Meeting, August, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Presidents Commission, Kansas City, MO, September, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Preview of Air Research Results, Washington, D.C., November, 1988 (Box 6)
    - General Information File, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
    - Presidents Commission to review Governance Process, 1989 (Box 6)
    - Advisory Committee to Review governance Process, 1989 (Box 6)
    - Advisory Committee to review the governance process, 1989 (Box 6)
    - Presidents Commission Meeting Westin O'Hare, Rosemont, IL, 1989 (Box 6)
    - Advisory Committee, Review of NCAA Governance Process, 1989 (Box 6)
    - Minutes of the National Athletic Association Presidents commission, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Presidents Commission, National Forum, Ryan Consultant, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Convention, San Francisco, CA, January 8-12, 1989 (Box 7)
    - National Forum Book, meeting Chicago, IL, April 29, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Meeting with President James Whalen, Ithica College, June, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Irvine Group, Task force, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
    - 84th Annual NCAA Convention, Dallas, TX, January 7-10, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Irvine Group, Ethics Task force, June 28-29, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Meeting in Lincoln, NE Wednesday, September 12, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Presidents Commission Meeting, Kansas City, MO, October 2, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Presidents Commission, Special meeting, Monday, December 3, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Presidents commission, legislative proposals, 1991 (Box 7)
    - Convention, Nashville, TN, January 7-11, 1991 (Box 7)
    - President Commission Meeting, June 24-26, 1991 (Box 7)
    - Presidents Commission, 1991-1992 (Box 7)
    - Annual Convention, Anaheim, CA, January 7-10, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Knight Commission, 1993 (Box 7)
    - News, Retrospective article on Presidents Commission, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
    - American Institutes for Research, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Committee on Athletics Certification, Peer Reviewer, 1996-1997 (Box 7)
    - Peer-Review Team Visit to the University of CA, Berkeley, October, 1997 (Box 7)
  - National Institute of Development Administration- Bankok, Thailand (NIDA) (see also AMARA), 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - New Venture Development Corporation (Jim Wolfe), 1998 (Box 7)
  - North Central Association of Colleges and Schools (NCA) Commission on Institutions of Higher Education- Self Study Report, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Oral History Archives of IU: (Box 7)
    - General, undated (Box 7)
    - Financial/Budget Information, undated (Box 7)
  - O, 2003-2004 (Box 7)
  - Oregon: (Box 7)
    - Governor's commission on Higher Education in the Portland Metropolitan Area (Box 7)
      - 1990-1992 (Box 7)
      - 1989 (Box 7)
      - July 14-16, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Byrne, John - Oregon State University President, 1988-1989 (Box 7)
    - Bound Reader, Portland Higher Education Reform, 1989 (Box 7a)
    - Bound Face Book, Oregon State University, 1988-1989 (Box 7a)
    - Bound Reader, Higher Education Reform, 1989 (Box 7a)
  - Orr, Gov. Robert, 1989 (Box 8)
  - P, 1989-2003 (Box 8)